hey everybody welcome to this a2
english listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening
and comprehension as i speak remember to
sign
up for our one dollar listening practice
seminars
at polyglossa.com and remember to
download
my free listening time podcast
so you can practice your listening
skills
so today i'm going to talk about job
interviews
this is an extremely important topic
because
usually in order to get a job you
need to pass a job interview many people
get nervous when they have to interview
for a job
because it can be intimidating or even
scary so why don't we discuss
some of the different elements of job
interviews
and maybe i can give you some tips that
might help you with
future interviews first of all let's
talk about the different
types of job interviews for example
there are one-on-one interviews and
there are group
interviews most interviews are typically
conducted
one-on-one but i've actually had one
or two group interviews before also
there are phone interviews video
interviews
and in-person interviews and
there are general interviews behavioral
interviews
and technical interviews the type of
questions you're asked
can be really different depending on the
type of
interview and the feel of the interview
can also be really different so for
example
preparing for a behavioral interview is
different than preparing for a technical
interview
you might be able to answer all the
technical questions well
but maybe you don't know how to answer
questions
about your personality or your
attributes
i help many english learners prepare
for job interviews in english and
usually
it's hard for them to answer general and
behavioral questions they can answer
technical questions easily but not the
more
general ones so let me teach you a good
structure
that you can use to answer general
questions
during interviews remember though that
i'm not an expert
this is just my opinion okay so
for general questions in job interviews
with
american employers you can structure
your answer like this
first restate the question
next introduce your main points
then explain each point in detail
and lastly restate the question again
let me give you a clear example of this
let's say they ask you the question why
should we hire you
here's how you can answer using the
structure i
showed you first restate the question
you should hire me because blah blah
blah
then introduce your main points you
should hire me
because i'm a responsible worker and
because
i'm a creative problem solver next
explain each point in detail explain
how you're a responsible worker and give
evidence for that and explain how
you're a creative problem solver and
give evidence for that
and lastly restate the question again
so this is why you should hire me
this structure might seem simple but
it's effective if you follow this
structure
when answering general questions you'll
sound more prepared and more
professional
of course if they ask you other types of
questions
the structure will be different for
example
if they ask you a behavioral question
like tell me about a time when you
overcame a difficult challenge
you should use the star method to answer
these types of questions
star stands for situation
task action result
so first you explain the situation
and give the context regarding the
difficult
challenge you faced then you describe
the task what your responsibility was
in that situation next you talk about
your actions
what you did to overcome the difficulty
and lastly you talk about the result
the outcome of your actions this formula
is a great way to answer behavioral
questions
and my last advice for you regarding job
interviews
is to be confident believe in yourself
and in your skills
and if the job interview is in english
make sure you prepare and memorize some
set phrases that you know you're gonna
use
good luck all right now i'm gonna ask
you some questions
about today's video to see how well you
understood
number one name two different types of
interviews
number two what's the first step
when answering general interview
questions
and number three what does the star
method stand for okay remember to sign
up for our one dollar
listening practice seminars and download
the listening time podcast for more
free listening practice also don't
forget to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram
i'll see you next time